明明有其他空牢房  你偏要把他們關在一起
You had another cell. You threw them in with him.
你算什么警察
What the hell kind of cop are you?
前情提要
你哥昨天被抓了
Your brother was arrested yesterday.
被告方有何辯護
How does the defendant plea?
無罪  法官閣下
Not guilty, your honor.
肯定挺費勁的
Could be a lot of work, I imagine.
要是把這么一大家子人都埋了  我們不會作證
Burying a family this large. We will not testify.
被告當庭釋放
The defendant is free to go.
我以為我再也見不到你了
I didn't think I'd see you again.
這座城市正處于暴風雨前的寧靜
This city is becoming a powder keg.
到時你不得不站隊
You're gonna have to pick your poison.
此事絕不容忍
This will not stand!
你就不該去那
You've got no business being out there at all.
把手放下
Drop your hands.
咱倆  兩清了吧
You and me, we're square now, right?
你該擔心的不是這個  比爾
You've got bigger concerns, Bill.
我要在街上見血
I'll need to see blood in the streets.
不  你們干什么
No! What are you doing?
帶上家人  今晚就離開舊金山
Take your family, and leave San Francisco tonight.
方塊7
我要籌碼
I'm gonna need a marker.
你聽見了嗎
Did you hear me?
我說要籌碼
I said I need a marker.
有什么問題嗎
What's the trouble here?
-杰克·達蒙  -比爾·歐哈拉
- Jack Damon. - Bill O'Hara.
天啊
Jesus.
你怎么跑這來了
What the hell are you doing here?
我聽說你離開軍隊
I heard you left the force
去芝加哥的平克頓偵探社了
to ride with the Pinkertons out in Chicago.
那邊太冷了
It's too fucking cold out there.
我秋天回舊金山了
I came back to San Francisco in the fall.
弗拉納根容不下我
Flannagan didn't have a slot for me,
所以我就來這了
so I ended up here.
你在這里工作
You work here?
豐海的金錢也一樣閃閃發光
Fung Hai gold shines as bright as anyone's.
你能讓他們拿籌碼給我嗎
Well, um, can you get them to stake me?
當然  五十夠嗎
Sure. How's about 50?
五十可以
Yeah, 50's good.
五十
50?
好運  比爾
Good luck, Bill.
紅心4
太棒了
Come on!
對不起各位
Sorry, fellas.
今晚不走運啊
Sometimes it's just not your night.
贏了不少啊
Nice pile.
相信我  剛才我還欠錢的
Believe me, I was due.
現在趕緊兌現吧
You know, now might be the right time to cash out.
盆盈缽滿地回家
Go home with your pockets full.
我正準備這么做
And that is exactly what I'm gonna do
等這輪結束的
just as soon as this action cools.
來吧  繼續轉
Let's go. Keep it spinning.
好吧  比爾
Okay, Bill.
請下注
黑桃1
我玩完了
I think I'm done.
-今晚不順嗎  -莊家作弊了
- Rough night? - Table's rigged.
真像個賭徒
Spoken like a true gambler.
來吧  我送你出去
Come on, I'll walk you out.
-我能還上籌碼  -我知道  比爾
- I'm good for my marker. - I know you are, Bill.
喘口氣  比爾
Short breaths, Bill.
放輕松
Easy, now.
我給你介紹一下豐海
Let me tell you something about the Fung Hai.
他們自稱是成吉思汗的直系后代
They believe they're direct descendants of Genghis Khan.
你知道蒙古人吧
You know the Mongols, right?
歷史上最大的帝國
Biggest empire in the history.
總之蒙古人
Anyway, the Mongols.
他們從平原策馬而來  就像一群
hey came riding out of the plains like...
惡魔
Demons.
掠奪整個城市
Pillaging whole cities.
如今中國人需要了解他們的敵人  對嗎
Now the Chinese, they need to understand their enemy, right?
所以皇帝派他的偵察兵去
So the Emperor sends his scouts out
蒙古平原
to the Mongolian plains,
他們到了那里  往遠處望去
and they get out there, and in the distance,
他們看到這座
they see this...
白色山峰
white mountain
拔地而起
rising up where no mountain should be.
他們離這座山越來越近
They get closer to this mountain,
你知道他們發現了什么嗎
and do you know what they find?
白骨
Bones.
一整座白骨山
An entire mountain of bones.
成千上萬的白骨
Hundreds of thousands of skeletons
爛成一堆
just rotting on a fucking pile.
那時他們才知道在和誰打交道
That's when they understood who they were dealing with...
你在和誰打交道
who you're dealing with.
豐海有個問題
The Fung Hai had a problem.
中國賭徒欠他們錢時
When a chink gambler owes them,
他們會打斷他的腿  威脅他的家人  但
they can break his legs, threaten his family, but...
當愛爾蘭人欠債后
what are they supposed to do when an Irishman runs up a debt
卻一走了之
and then runs back down the hill
他們該怎么辦
when it comes time to pay?
老達蒙就上場了
That's where old Damon comes in.
我可以做到他們不能做的
See, I can go where they can't--
殺一儆百
make an example of someone,
確保每個人都知道代價
make sure everyone knows the toll.
就算警察也逃不掉豐海的債
Not even a cop escapes a Fung Hai debt.
你怎么混到這份上了
How do you live with yourself,
做中國佬的打手
being a stick boy for the chinks?
我不喜歡這樣  比爾
I take no pleasure in it, Bill.
但我在那里為你擔保了
But I vouched for you in there,
所以你要付錢
so you're going to pay up.
標準期限為兩周
Standard window is two weeks.
我給警察一個特惠
I'll give you the policeman's special:
三周
three weeks.
之后
After that...
你就要去白骨山一游了
You're taking a trip to the white mountain.
去你媽的  達蒙
Fuck you, Damon.
三周  比爾
Three weeks, Bill.
第一季  第四集
市廳警察
早啊  阿杉
Morning, Ah Sahm.
-早啊  -早上好  阿杉
- Morning. - Morning, Ah Sahm.
時間到了
Hey, about time!
-感覺怎么樣  -呼吸時才會疼
- How's it feel? - It only hurts when I breathe.
還有坐下時
And sit.
你覺得這就算糟糕嗎
You think that's bad?
看看這個
Look at this.
我總是隨身攜帶
I always carry it with me.
讓我想起去過的地方
Reminds me of where I've been.
這是什么
What is it?
一枚鐵路道釘
It's a railroad spike.
博洛曾在洲際鐵路工作
Bolo used to work on the Transcontinental.
你當過苦力
You were a coolie?
猶他
Utah.
夏天熱得要命
Hot as hell in the summer.
冬天冷死人
Cold as fuck in the winter.
沒過多久美國佬
It didn't take long for the ducks to find
就發現了他的長處
a better use for him.
你在和傳奇人物說話
You're talking to a legend, man.
大約十年前
About ten years ago,
據說有個強大的中國人
word spread of a giant Chinaman
在斯康鐵路上戰斗
fighting on the Transcon circuit.
他無人能敵
There was no one he couldn't take down.
他們稱之為黃魔
They called him "The Yellow Demon."
閉嘴吧  小尊
Shut the fuck up, Baby Jun.
黃魔
"The Yellow Demon"?
我父親想親眼目睹一下
My father had to see it for himself,
所以他大老遠跑到猶他州
so he travelled all the way to Utah
就為好好看一眼這個所謂的惡魔
to get a better look at this so-called demon.
那只不過是又一場
It was just another game
供無聊的白豬賭錢的游戲
for the bored white fucks to bet on.
殺人能拿雙份錢
They paid the fighters double for kills,
黃魔每次都會拿到這筆獎金
and the Yellow Demon always got that bonus.
我父親
My father...
不能容忍讓美國佬
couldn't stand the thought of some duck
利用博洛賺錢
getting rich off Bolo's back,
所以把他買下來了
so he bought him.
"把他買下來了"是什么意思
What do you mean, "bought him"?
像買頂帽子嗎
Like a hat?
別自欺欺人了
Don't kid yourself.
你這臭蔥頭的命是尊爺的
Father Jun owns your onion ass,
我們的命都是他的
just like he owns the rest of us.
來吧  你看起來糟透了
Come on, you look like shit.
我有東西能幫上忙
I've got something that will help with that.
總有一天
One of these days,
咱倆應該過幾招
you and I should go a few rounds...
試試身手
see what's what.
跟黃魔打
Fight the Yellow Demon?
我瘋了嗎
Do I look crazy?
注意
Ten-hut.
副市長先生  早上好
Mr. Deputy Mayor. Good morning.
弗拉納根局長  我知道你是個大忙人
Chief Flannagan, I know you're a busy man,
所以我就直說了
so I'll get right to it.
我想你一定和我一樣
I am sure you were as disappointed as I was
對法官決定釋放
in the judge's decision
你手下抓到的惡徒一事感到失望
to cut loose the highbinder your men arrested.
這他媽就是嘲弄  就是這樣
It was a fucking travesty, is what it was.
你一定能想象到  我們有一群憤怒的選民
As you can imagine, we have a very angry constituency
在要求伸張正義
demanding justice.
-毫無疑問  -局長
- No doubt. - Chief,
你干這行很久了
you've been at it a long time.
二十五年
25 years.
我想說的是  像你這么有經驗的人
My point is, a man of your experience knows
明白我們的法庭  法官和法律
that from time to time, our courts, judges--
有時候不能伸張真正的正義
our laws can fail to deliver true justice.
這種時候  就需要我們行政部門
At those times, it falls to us in the executive branch
負責收拾殘局  可以這么說
to pick up the slack, as it were.
我記得這段對話開始時
As I recall, you started this conversation
你說要"有話直說"
by saying you planned to get "right to it."
中國城的暴力是持續存在的問題
Violence in Chinatown is an ongoing problem.
但如果蔓延到中國城之外
When it spills out of Chinatown,
我們就不能容忍了
that is something we cannot tolerate.
市長想要殺雞儆猴
The mayor would like to send a message.
那么
And, uh,
市長有看上的地點嗎
does the mayor have any particular venue in mind?
那好吧
All right, then.
李子  比爾去哪了
Leeds! Where the hell is Bill?
我們要的是殺手
We ask for killers...
結果只有這種貨色
and this is what we get.
悠著點  伙計  這玩意勁大
Go easy, man. This shit kicks.
-里面加了什么  -只是一點點鴉片膏
- What's in this? - It's just a kiss of molasses.
特殊情況下我才會這么卷
I only roll them on special occasions...
今天的情況就是我爸昨晚
the occasion here being the major up-fuckery
狠揍了你一頓
my father laid on you last night.
知道嗎  我的比你更慘
Mine was worse, you know.
我的入堂儀式被他打斷兩根骨頭
Broke two bones in his own hands skinning me in.
真見鬼
Fucking hell.
他不想讓人覺得有所偏袒
He didn't want to show any favoritism.
你知道你能相信我吧
You know you can trust me, right?
-我知道  -很好
- I know. - Good.
因為我比看上去要聰明
'Cause I'm smarter than I look.
你必須得聰明才行
Well, you'd have to be.
去你的  你個狗逼
Fuck off, you dog cunt.
你為什么來這里
Why are you here?
別告訴我是為了麻煙
And don't tell me it's for the chop.
像你這么能打的人
A guy who can scrap like you
不需要跨海來掙錢
doesn't need to cross the salt to get paid.
我來找一個人
I came to find someone.
那個姑娘
The girl.
我就知道
I knew it!
好吧  但是不能每次我一扭頭
Well, now, I can't have you fucking off every time
-你就不見了...  -她死了
- I turn around-- - She's dead.
她死了
She's dead.
對
Yeah.
你跨過大海
You cross the salt.
結果她死了
She ends up dead.
現在你入堂了
Now you're skinned in.
你可真倒霉
Sucks for you.
我也不知道
I don't know, uh...
我一個人過了很長時間
I've been on my own for a while...
所以很高興知道有人挺我
so it's kind of good to know someone has my back.
這么想就對了
That's the spirit.
你知道  這是雙向的
Works both ways, you know.
-什么  -信任
- What? - Trust.
我需要知道我能信任你
I need to know I can trust you.
你能
You can.
這玩意讓我頭暈
This shit is making me woozy.
我去走走
I'm gonna go walk it off.
沒問題
Sure.
別再從我面前消失就行
Just don't go disappearing on me again.
我想你一定會喜歡這個
I think you're really gonna like this.
我不是來買東西的
I'm not here to shop.
反正也來了  順便看一眼
But you are here, so just take a look.
你看
See that?
假如你發現自己陷入困境
Now, suppose you find yourself in a tight spot.
砰
Bang.
你學得很快
You learn fast.
我給你個好價錢
I'll give you a good price.
別再跟我推銷了
Stop trying to sell me.
我是來找你談豐海的
I came here to talk to you about the Fung Hai.
豐海
Fung Hai?
我需要你安排會面
I need you to set a meeting.
豐海
Fung Hai.
聽我說
Now, look...
我知道你需要新的打手來收尾
I know you need new scissor boys to help round things out,
這我可以幫你
and I can help you with that.
-但是豐海...  -阿舟
- But the Fung Hai... - Chao.
你知道  他們建起長城
You know, they built the Great Wall
就是為了阻擋像豐海那幫人一樣的野蠻人
to keep out savages like the Fung Hai.
相信我  跟他們打交道沒有好下場
Trust me, no good will come from dealing with them.
如果我是來征求你的意見的
And if I'd come for your advice,
一定很樂意和你爭論  但我不是
I'm sure I'd love the debate, but I didn't.
我是來讓你安排會面的
See, what I did do was ask you to set a meeting.
你可以答應  然后掙到賞錢
So you can say yes and earn your fee
和我的謝意  或者你可以拒絕
and my gratitude, or you can say no
然后空手而歸
and earn neither.
好  行
Sure. Okay.
請盡快安排
As soon as possible, please.
你自己看
See for yourself.
他一團糟
He's a mess.
被苦力打個半死  黎明時候才回來
Came home at dawn beaten half to death by coolies.
我跟你說了
I already told you,
他們的下場比我慘得多
they fared much worse by the time it was over.
我沒想到他們會偷襲我  就這樣
I was caught by surprise, that's all.
我沒想到的是
The only surprise here
你還能活下來繼續騙我
is that you're still alive to lie about it.
現在我有點后悔活下來了
And right about now, I'm wishing I wasn't.
老天  有人把你
God, somebody jumped on you
胖揍了一頓啊
with all four feet, didn't they?
按理說隊長不用值夜班吧
You'd think the head of a squad wouldn't work the night shift.
別糾纏不休了  我說了我沒事
Quit your badgering. I said I'm fine.
對  你說的話多了去了  比爾
Yes, you say a lot of things, Bill.
你呢  你當時怎么沒和他在一起
And you? Why weren't you there with him?
別煩他  他這周都值了三個夜班了
Leave him alone! He's had three night shifts this week!
抱歉  李先生  我就是覺得太過分了
Sorry, Mr. Lee, I just think it's unconscionable,
派他晚上獨自一人去那種地方
sending him into that place alone at night.
相信我  歐哈拉太太  你再說也無濟于事
Believe me, Mrs. O'Hara, you're preaching to the choir.
我們已經跟局長說過加班的事情
We've spoken to the chief about doubling up on shifts,
但我想你也知道  一談到預算
but as I'm sure you know when it comes to budgets,
市政絕不妥協
the city's as tight as a fiddle string.
常言說得好"人窮面子不能窮
As they say, "Too poor to paint,
人倒架子不能倒"
too proud to whitewash."
我聞到了咖啡香味嗎
Is that coffee I smell brewing?
因為我現在非常想來一杯
Because Lord Almighty, I could sure use a cup.
我給你倒
I'll go pour you one.
非常感謝  太太
Much obliged, ma'am.
我操
Jesus fuck!
你能幫我穿襪子嗎
Can you help me with my socks?
我沒法...
I can't...
你在等什么
What you waiting for?
我以為昨晚是斯通去巡邏墳場
I thought Stone was on the graveyard shift last night.
你可真是個機靈的偵探啊  李
Well, that is some solid fucking detective work, Lee.
給我好好穿鞋就行了
Just help me with my boots.
鞋帶系雙結  閉上你的嘴
Double-knot the laces and shut the fuck up.
回去前我要把這個包好
I'm gonna pick that up before we head back.
-我們去哪  -你覺得呢
- Where are we going? - Where do you think?
-遠嗎  -你隨時可以回去
- Is it far? - You could always turn around.
不好意思  你是不是對我有意見  雅各布
I'm sorry, do you have some kind of problem with me, Jacob?
我見過的美國地盤比你多得多
I've seen a lot more of the pond than you,
聽我一句  跟著我沒有好處
so listen to me when I say no good will come from following me.
明白嗎
Get me?
但她派你來找我
But she sent you for me.
我可以告訴她你讓我滾犢子
I can tell her you told me to fuck off.
你是擔心她
Are you worried about her,
還是擔心自己
or yourself?
沒區別
Doesn't matter.
對我們大家都沒好處
Ends badly for all of us.
謝謝你的顧慮  雅各布
I appreciate your concern, Jacob,
但我想知道你的女主人要說什么
but I think I'll just see what your duck lady has to say.
下午好  巴克利先生
Afternoon, Mr. Buckley.
卡爾森小姐
Miss Carlson.
他在哪里
Where is he?
該死
God damn it.
巴克利
Buckley!
你在這干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
舊金山警局
San Francisco Police Department.
都不許動
Nobody move.
好了
All right.
讓我們看看還有哪個臭小子能站起來
Let's see which of these fuckers can actually stand.
行動  起來
All right, let's go. On your feet.
別擋我的路
Get the fuck out of my way.
醒醒
Wakey-wakey!
太陽曬屁股了  你們這些墮落的混蛋
All right, rise and shine, you fucking degenerates.
拜托
Come on.
-市長先生  -隊長
- Mr. Mayor. - Sergeant.
李
Lee.
妓女都在樓上
The whores are upstairs.
把所有中國佬都給我抓起來
I want every slant-eyed john you can get your hands on.
你  你  起來
You, you. Get out of here.
怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
接著走  你不需要知道
Keep moving, you won't have to find out.
把中國佬帶去車那邊
Move the slants to the wagon.
怎么  你想玩玩
Yeah? You want to play?
天哪
Ah, Jesus.
你還在等什么
What are you waiting for?
快點  別管那個
Come on. Never mind that.
-照我說的做  -快走  走
- Do as I say and-- - Move along, move along.
快點
Come on.
你想用斧頭砍我  是不是
You want to pull a hatchet on me, do you?
出來  變態
Get out here, pervert!
你還好嗎
Are you all right?
趕緊干活  懂嗎
Just make yourself useful, will you?
警察
Police!
你還知道來
Nice of you to show up.
這里怎么了
What happened here?
他襲擊我
He drew on me.
我差點嚇得尿褲子
I almost pissed my fucking pants.
把其他中國佬都關進車里
Get the rest of these chinks in the wagon
-然后我們撤  -這是什么情況
- and let's get the fuck out of here. - What is meaning of this?
你是亞彩
You're Ah Toy.
-你認識我  -大家都認識你
- You know me. - Everyone knows you.
我得到了命令關閉這里
I have orders to shut you down,
并且逮捕你
and I'm placing you under arrest.
逮捕
Arrest?
因為什么
What for?
你在經營妓院
You're running a brothel.
妓院
Brothel?
不
No.
這是間寄宿屋  住的都是好姑娘
This a boarding house. These are good girls.
你跟法官說去吧
You can tell that to the judge.
如果我們做朋友
It would be better...
不是更好嗎
if we were friends, no?
朋友  是嗎
Friends, huh?
給您拜個早年
Early gift for Chinese New Year.
我們也要逮捕她嗎
Should we take her in too?
不必了
Nah.
我們完活了
I think we're done here.
謝謝您的配合  女士
Thank you for your cooperation, ma'am.
你有話想說
You got something you want to say?
不  無話可說
Nope, nothing I want to say.
聽著  我不知道你以為自己看見了什么
Look, I don't know what you think you saw in there--
我什么也沒想
I don't think anything.
你個自以為是的小賤貨
You preachy little shit!
你以為受點小賄就是問題嗎
You think taking a little money here is the problem?
睜大你的狗眼吧
Open your fucking eyes.
整個掃黃才是真正的問題
This whole bust is the problem.
你  我  那些中國佬  中國城警隊
You, me, the goddamn chinks, the Chinatown squad,
我們都只是別人棋盤中的棋子
we're all just pawns in someone else's game,
別大驚小怪了  我不過是想
so sue me if I'm getting my back scratched
在別人捅我刀子前撈點好處
before they stick a fucking knife in it!
那是非對錯呢
What about right and wrong?
"是非對錯"
"Right and wrong."
你到底為什么來這里  李
Why are you even here, Lee?
什么
What?
我猜薩瓦納也有很多罪犯吧
Well, I presume they've got plenty of criminals in Savannah.
為什么一個南方男孩要大老遠地
Why does a southern boy like you have to come all the way out here
跑到沒人認識你的地方當警察
where nobody knows who the fuck you are to become a cop?
聽好了
I'll tell you what.
你走你的陽關道
You stay the fuck out of my business,
我走我的獨木橋
and I'll stay the fuck out of yours.
還有其他需要嗎  夫人
Anything else, missus?
不用了  謝謝  雅各布  你下去吧
No, thank you, Jacob. That will be all.
所有美國人都有兩個家嗎
Does everyone in America have two homes?
樓是我父親的
My father owns the building.
你為什么派雅各布來找我
Why'd you send Jacob for me?
你為什么來
Why did you come?
我猜是好奇吧
Curious, I guess.
我只是...
I just...
我很后悔上次見面的情形
I regretted our last meeting.
我想讓你知道我不是那樣的人
I want you to know I'm not like that.
哪樣的人
Like what?
我說不好  只是覺得自己該道歉
I don't know, I just thought I should apologize.
真是個不咋地的道歉
That was a terrible apology.
你想喝點茶嗎
Would you like some tea?
行
Sure.
這些都是你畫的
You painted all of these?
嗯
Yeah.
你說你祖父是美國人
So, you said your grandfather was American.
他是個船長
He was a sea captain.
他為一家茶葉公司做海上貿易
He sailed the trade routes for a tea company.
有一年  他病了
One year he, uh-- he got sick.
沒辦法回到美國
He couldn't make the trip back home to America.
中國商人幫他安頓下來  請一名年輕護士
The Chinese merchants put him up with a young nurse
照顧他  度過了冬天
who cared for him through the winter.
他們墜入愛河  搬進一家小農場
They fell in love and moved to a small farm.
我出生后不久  祖母就去世了
My grandmother died when I was a baby,
但我祖父一直和我們生活在農場
but my grandfather lived on the farm with us
他是在我13歲那年去世的
until he passed when I was about 13...
他教我和我妹妹學英語
taught my sister and me English,
還給我們講了很多美國的故事
filled our heads with stories about America.
所以你才想來美國
So that's why you wanted to come to America.
我并不想來
I didn't want to come.
為什么還是來了
Then why did you?
我從沒給任何人看過這些畫
I've never shown those to anyone before.
為什么
Why not?
沒有人來過這里
No one's ever been here...
你是第一個
before you.
這樣的話
Well, um...
我很榮幸
I'm honored.
你應該感到榮幸
You should be.
你到底為什么會來
So why did you really come?
來美國嗎
To America?
這里
Here.
和你請我來的原因一樣
For the same reason you asked me to.
我不知道為什么叫你來
I don't know why I asked you to.
我覺得你知道
I think you do.
你很自信
You're very sure of yourself.
這是我的缺點
It's a problem.
謝謝你同意和我們見面
Thank you for agreeing to meet with us.
我們非常敬佩
We have great respect for what the Fung Hai
豐海在自己地盤上的成就
have accomplished in your territory,
我們有一個提議
and we have a proposition for you.
我不喜歡多嘴的賤人
I don't like when these bitches talk so much.
你喜歡聽她們啰嗦嗎
You like it when they talk so much?
也許你應該聽一聽
Perhaps you should listen.
豐海不需要任何人的幫助
The Fung Hai don't need help from anyone,
尤其是由婊子出面交涉的堂口
especially not some tong that lets the pussy do the talking.
其實
You know,
我早就預料到你會有這種反應
I had a feeling that you might feel this way.
賤人還在說話
The bitch is still talking.
所以我已經把你殺了
Which is why I already killed you.
你這個賤人
You bitch!
好了
So...
你剛剛說有個提議
I understand you have a proposition.
李勇
Li Yong.
剛剛是怎么回事
What the fuck was that?
他絕對不會和我們做交易的
He was never going to deal.
我們做了其他安排
We made other arrangements.
卻沒有告訴我
Without telling me, hmm?
為什么要告訴你
Why would I tell you?
如果我安排一次見面
See, if I set up a meet
而其中一方沒有離開
and someone doesn't walk out,
我的聲譽就毀了
that fucks with my reputation.
但如果我們告訴了你
And if we had told you,
你還會安排嗎
would you have done it?
我肯定會提高價錢
I definitely would have charged more.
李勇
Li Yong.
豐海
The Fung Hai?
是了結的手段
A means to an end.
也許吧
Maybe.
了結誰呢
But whose end?
你從哪里學會那樣打架的
Where did you learn to fight like that?
中國人都會那樣打架
All Chinese people can fight like that.
真的嗎
Really?
假的
No.
但你是...
But you're, uh...
惡棍
a highbinder...
黑幫殺手
a gang enforcer.
你不像是這樣的人
That doesn't seem like you.
我從船上下來后
I didn't have a lot of options
并沒有太多選擇的余地
when I got off the boat.
為了找到妹妹  加入合威是最好的選擇
Joining the Hop Wei was the best shot at finding my sister.
你妹妹
Your sister?
結果發現她不想被我找到
Turns out she didn't want to be found.
我嫁給我丈夫
I married my husband...
是為了拯救我父親的公司
to save my father's company.
我小的時候母親就去世了
My mother died when I was little,
所以基本上是我把妹妹們養大
so I practically raised my sisters,
當生意開始衰敗...
and when the business started to fail...
我不能讓她們承受那樣的結果
Well, I couldn't just let that happen to them.
布萊克家是舊金山的首富之一
The Blakes are one of the wealthiest families
而且塞繆爾是市長
in San Francisco, and Samuel was the mayor.
他和我父親是朋友
He was a friend of my father's,
母親去世后  他經常來探望
and he visited a lot after my mother died.
他總是保持微笑  還給我帶硬糖吃
He always had a smile and a hard candy for me.
隨著我逐漸長大
And as I got older...
他的笑容變了
his smile changed.
有了別的意義
It became something else.
但那份市政府合同
But that city contract
是讓我家免于破產的
was all that stood between my family
唯一解藥
and financial ruin.
我不記得具體是什么時候決定的
I don't remember exactly when I made the decision,
但有一天  我...
but one day I just...
回應了他的微笑
smiled back.
我猜...
I guess...
我像你一樣出賣了自己
I sold myself the same way you did.
這不適合你
Doesn't suit you.
被人占有
Being owned.
我覺得你我都不適合這種生活
I don't think it suits either of us.
起來  下一個是你
Come on, you're next.
你們撰寫報道時  最好說明
As you write your stories, you may want to note
這只是大規模突襲的開始
that this raid will be the first of many
市長要對中國城開展積極行動
as part of the mayor's aggressive Chinatown initiative.
你們絕對安全  先生們
No, you're perfectly safe, gentlemen.
不需要擔心
There's no need for concern.
-這樣就好看多了  -別動
- Look better after this. - Stay still.
-先生們  -市長先生
- Gentlemen. - Mr. Mayor.
看來一切進展順利
Well, it looks like we're making some progress.
好了
Now...
注意穿黑西裝的人
keep your eye on the ones in the black suits.
那是中國黑幫的裝束
That is the uniform of the Chinese gangsters.
他們是中國最冷酷的罪犯
These are the most hardened criminals in China.
來到這里的都是這種人
That's who's coming over here.
像美國這樣的
A land of laws and grace
法治與高雅之邦經受不住
like the United States is all too vulnerable
這些外國犯罪分子的侵蝕
to this foreign criminal element.
我們必須鐵面無情  先生們
We've got to harden our hearts, gentlemen.
-可以把那張印出來  -等等
- You can print that. - Oh, wait.
等等  等一下
Wait, hold on.
我們拍張照吧
Let's get a picture.
弗拉納根局長  把你的人都叫來
Chief Flannagan, let's get all of your men together.
中國城警隊全體隊員
The whole Chinatown squad.
我想把你們的辛勤工作
I want to document the good work
-記錄下來  -比爾  麥克勞德
- you're doing here. - Bill, McLeod,
哈里森  斯通  過來
Harrison, Stone, come here.
市長先生
Mr. Mayor?
我們剛剛經歷了戰爭  拯救了美國
We just fought a war to save America.
不能轉過頭就將這個國家交給中國人
We're not gonna turn around and hand it over to the Chinese.
我們要把這些人趕回老家去
We need to send these boys back where they came from.
要是繼續給他們剪頭發
Well, you keep cutting off their hair,
他們就回不去了
they won't be able to go back.
閉嘴  李
Shut up, Lee.
你說什么  警官
What was that, officer?
這是中國的法律  巴克利先生
It's the law in China, Mr. Buckley.
根據皇帝的旨意
By decree of the Emperor, all men are required
男人得留長辮
to wear those braided queues.
他不是有意的  先生
He doesn't mean anything by it, sir.
李警官就是一個歷史迷而已
Officer Lee is just a bit of a history buff, that's all.
-李  是嗎  -是的  先生
- Lee, is it? - Yes, sir.
李警官  過來拍照
Get in the picture, Officer Lee.
不  謝了  先生
Uh, no thank you, sir.
我真的不喜歡拍照
I don't really like having my picture taken.
快去拍照  李
Get in the fucking picture, Lee.
別動
Hold still.
我一直想問你
Been meaning to ask you:
你的臉怎么了
What the hell happened to your face?
說來話長
Long story.
我可能不想聽
It's one I probably don't want to hear.
應該是吧
Probably not.
大家都別動
All right, everybody stand still.
別動
Nobody move.
來自東方的外來疾病
Exotic diseases from the Orient.
中國幫派暴力正在蔓延
Chinese gang violence that's spilling
進入白人社區
into white neighborhoods.
空地上都是失業的美國人
Sandlots full of unemployed Americans.
目前可能是區域性的  但如果不加以控制
It may feel local today, but if it goes unchecked,
黃禍會像瘟疫一樣蔓延全國
the yellow peril will spread across the country like a plague.
廉價報社更好賣
The Penny Press is an easier sell,
流通量也很大
and their circulation is substantial.
但我知道你為什么
But I understand why you would think
想讓美聯社報道這個新聞
that the Associated Press should be covering this story.
中國對美國價值觀的攻擊
"The Chinese Assault on American Values."
這是標題
That's your headline.
請你上車好嗎
Would you just get in, please?
謝謝你送我
Thanks for the ride.
真高端
Fancy.
大家都說
You know, everyone always said
你是個功夫奇才
you were a kung fu prodigy.
我覺得你真正的天賦
I think your real genius...
是給我找麻煩
Is finding ways to screw up my life.
我也很高興見到你
It's good to see you too.
你剛到這里
You just got here,
就加入了我的敵對幫派
and already you've joined my enemies,
坐了牢
gotten yourself arrested--
你上的不止是白人妹子
not only are you fucking a white lady,
那可是市長夫人
you're fucking the mayor's wife.
下周你還打算干嗎
What are you going to do next week?
你這么一說
Well, when you put it like that--
-我說了讓你離開  -我是打算走的
- I told you to leave. - Oh, and I was going to,
但后來我想起來你不是我的老板
but then I remembered you're not my boss.
你真的認為父親讓你來美國
Do you really think Father would have wanted you
就是讓你被殺嗎
to cross the salt just to get yourself killed?
他想讓你在美國佬的監獄被關到死
He'd want you rotting away in a duck prison?
對了  謝謝救我出來
Oh, thanks, by the way, for getting me out.
真是太好了  救了我一命
That was great. Really saved my ass.
一如既往
As usual.
我救你最后一次
I'm gonna do it one final time.
送你回家
I'm sending you home.
太平洋郵輪
跟我一起走
Come with me.
阿杉
Ah Sahm...
我回不去了
I'm never going back.
-我在中國誰也不是  -不
- I'm nobody in China... - No,
-你不走我就不走  -你在這里誰也不是
- I'm not going without you. - And you're nobody here.
堂口之間必有一戰
There is going to be a war between the tongs...
如果你站錯了隊
and if you're on the wrong side,
我不會猶豫的
I won't hesitate.
我不能猶豫
I can't.
你的船明天出發
Your boat leaves tomorrow.
你說得對
You were right.
什么
What?
我不應該讓你嫁給孫楊來救我
I should never have let you marry Sun Yang to save me.
我應該拼命救你的
I should have fought to save you.
我不會再犯這種錯誤了
I'm not gonna make that mistake again.
我以為你回家睡覺了
I figured you'd be home and in bed by now.
你有四個孩子的時候再說這話吧
Come and talk to me when you've got four kids.
不是五個嗎
I thought it was five?
操  我老是把伊桑忘了
Fuck me. I keep forgetting Ethan.
他也是我的最愛
He's my favorite too.
喝點什么嗎
You want a drink?
還是說你不喝酒了
Or don't you drink anymore?
你也把這個嗜好也留在喬治亞了
You left all that behind in Georgia too?
恰恰相反
Oh, on the contrary,
我媽最煩我了
I'm the only hell my mama ever raised.
那就喝一杯吧
Well, come on, then.
兩杯
Two.
說吧
Well, let's go. Out with it.
說什么
With what?
我不知道
Oh, I don't know...
但你總是有問題
But it's always something with you.
好吧
Right, well, um...
我只是想道個歉
I guess I just wanted to apologize.
道歉我喜歡
Well, this sounds promising.
你是我的上級
You are the superior officer,
比我更了解道上的事
and you know the streets better than I do.
我不應該質疑你的
I shouldn't be questioning you.
沒錯
You're damn right about that.
你真是一只奇怪的鳥  李
You're a strange bird, Lee.
為什么
How's that?
首先
Well, for starters,
大多數警察不會掏死人的肚子
most cops don't dig around in the guts of dead men.
其實吧
Well...
我之前一直住在農場
I spent my whole life on a farm.
牛死了  就得檢查一下體內
Cows start dying, you gotta look inside,
看看它們的死因
see what's killing them.
人不是動物
People aren't animals.
不是嗎
Aren't we?
我們不過是被大腦欺騙了
We've just got these bigger brains that trick us
自以為不是動物
into thinking we're something else.
給
Here you are.
記我賬上
Put it on my tab.
你是好孩子
Look, you're a good kid...
也會成為一個好警察的
and you're gonna be a fine cop.
我能看出來  因為我曾經也是
And I should know. I used to be one.
總有一天
One of these days,
我們會調離中國城
we'll get ourselves reassigned out of Chinatown
去做些真正的警察工作
and we'll go off and do some real police work.
好嗎
All right?
聽起來不錯  隊長
Sounds good, Sergeant.
但在那之前
But until then,
低調一點
you keep your head down.
活下來就行
You do what you have to to survive.
在中國城巡邏
This Chinatown beat...
黑白兩道能讓你有
there's about 100 different ways it can bury you...
將近一百種死法
on both sides of the line.
你明白嗎
Do you understand?
明白
I do.
不  你不明白
No, you don't.
暫時還不明白
Not yet.
但你會明白的
But you will.
很抱歉  雖然你還沒喝完  但我得走了
I'm sorry to leave you before you finish your drink,
我有約
but I've got an appointment.
加我一個
Deal me in.
你知道菲茨說我不能再給你籌碼了  比爾
You know Fitz says I can't give you any more markers, Bill.
買入價十塊
The buy-in is $10.
這有三十
Here's 30.